Welcome to this advanced javascript course way you will learn concepts and techniques to transform you
from a junior javascript developer to a senior javascript guru.
My name is ask him and I have over the years experience building applications for clients such as the
European Space Agency and Google.
I've also been a take BP at JP Morgan and Morgan Stanley investment banks.
Now I run my own digital agency in London called bubble gum and we build apps for awesome clients all
over the world and I also teach javascript angular J.S. and I only development through my company cockcrow
.
So there are already a bunch of advanced javascript courses out there.
Why should you take this one.
Number one is because I value your time.
If you are even a fraction as busy as I am then your time is incredibly important to me.
So I don't waste time.
I've created this course to pass along the maximum knowledge with the minimum time.
Now notice I didn't say minimum after this will be three hours of hard work but I promise you after
only three hours you'll have leveled up your javascript knowledge.
Now the second reason I say it picked this cause is that the former is all really unique.
I'm going to teach you all of these advanced topics through a series of interview questions.
We all get lazy in our jobs.
We all get comfortable with our level of knowledge and only when faced with an interview because it
forces us to try and verify our assumptions and deepen our knowledge.
It also makes for a pretty focused and practical course.
Take this in preparation for an interview or perhaps you're hiring.
I want to make sure you're asking the right questions.
Or maybe you just want the knowledge to be a better developer.
Whatever the reason if you want to become a senior javascript developer This cost is the cost for you
.
So what are you actually going to learn.
We are going to cover a number of topics in the form of a series of interview questions.
Now a third is going to cover just some really important basics such as what to do.
Use strict keyword do and does javascript pass by reference or by value with Dangote to cover the concepts
of equality and types in Javascript.
So what are the different types and how do you actually make sure that two things are equal in javascript
then going to cover the broad topic of scopes in javascript so we go going to discuss the different
scopes so variable can be declared in.
We're going to discuss variable hoisting.
We're going to discuss the scope chain.
We're going to ask what are I f is.
I'm going to ask what function closures with anger and to discuss the thorny topic of object orientation
in javascript.
We don't see discussing explain what the this key word actually means.
We're going to also explain what we call bind and apply functions do and we're then going to apply that
knowledge and discuss two different competing objects orientated methodologies and javascript's with
both the prototype pattern and the constructor pattern.
We're then going to cover two topics and network.
I believe every SR javascript developers should know and know in detail and that is what is called The
Cross origin resource sharing and what is Jason P..
I'm going to finish with some advanced questions on events and event handling under the hood.
In javascript the ideal student for this course is an existing javascript developer.
We won't be covering any of the basics on this course at the very least you need to know how to declare
variables in javascript.
How to Create and call functions how to perform loops in javascript and breakouts of those leaves and
also how to perform string manipulation and you must have already built a javascript application of
at least a thousand lines of code.
Now if that sounds like you feel free to take a look at the course description preview any of the lectures
and I look forward to seeing you on the inside
.